## JANET YODER

7205 W. 21st. Street Greeley, CO 80634 kajcyoder@comcast.net

www.linkedin.com/in/janetyoder Cell: 970-396-9428

### **SUMMARY**

Accomplished professional that is combining a strong software development background with fresh Web development skills. Top strengths include: excellent interpersonal skills, utilizing teamwork to get results, and being detail-oriented without losing sight of the overall goal. Experience in:

- Designing, building, editing web sites
- Responsive design
- Knowledgeable in Adobe Suite
- Product/Project/Program Management
- Scrum Master and Agile practices
- Escalation Management and process creation

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Visual Studio, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML/HTML5, CSS3, C++, C#, COM, MFC, XML
- Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Microsoft Project, PowerPoint, Word, Excel, Visio, SharePoint
- Subversion, GitHub, Brackets, HP Quality Center/ALM, XPlanner, VMWare, InstallShield

### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

Front Range Community College Longmont, CO

WebLab - A Web Development Boot Camp, FRCC Certificate (2014)

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, UI/UX Design

Aims Community College Greeley, CO

**Graphics Software and Applications Certificate (2014)** 

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign CS5 and CS6, Typography and Layout, Electronic Pre-press

## **Complete Web Authoring Class (2014)**

HTML5 and CSS3 – Created a 5 page website for the final project.

University of Northern Colorado Greeley, CO

Bachelor of Arts, Mathematics, Emphasis: Computer Science

## **Corporate Sponsored Training**

- 2012-2013 Writing Windows 8 Metro Applications with XAML, Windows Store Data binding and MVVM
- 2010 2012 Agile Estimating and Planning, Coaching Agile Teams, Demonstrating Responsibility: The Mindset of an Agile Leader, Designing the Agile, Organization Who Does What, Certified Scrum Master Training, Windows CE Development, Microsoft SharePoint 2010
- 2004-2007 Project Management, Program Management, Project Leadership and Communication, TCP/IP Workshop, Managing Offshore Vendors
- 1999-2003 Java, Fundamentals of XML, Programming with C#, Power ASP .NET Programming
- Prototyped with C# on writing Window 8 applications for the Windows Store. Owner of the submission of my team's HP Scan and Capture application to the Windows Store.
- Prototyped how to do a scan from a web page using HTML and EZTWAIN.

Janet Yoder Page 2

### KEY PROJECTS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

To view the websites and source code go to: <a href="http://jcyoder.github.io/">http://jcyoder.github.io/</a>

### The Kitchen Web Site

This five page site uses HTML5 and CSS3 to demonstrate the use of HTML forms, a Google form, an embedded Google map, tables, iframes, @media for responsive design and a small amount of jQuery.

## **Todos Web Application**

Todos demonstrates the use of HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery to allow users to add, remove, edit, cross off, and filter todo list items.

#### Calculator

This tool uses HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript event handlers to create a basic calculator.

### Colorado Travel

Main page example showing the use of jQuery event handlers for menu/submenu navigation and the use of responsive design.

## **Adobe Suite Projects**

- InDesign 2015 calendar, magazine layout, 8 page booklet
- Illustrator Building created with perspective tool, coffee mug drawn with pen and gradient mesh tools, playing card deck design, personal portrait
- Photoshop Food Magazine cover, photo collage, posters

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## HEWLETT-PACKARD, Greeley/Fort Collins, CO

1993-2013

## **Sustained Engineering Lead for Windows Software (2013)**

Led the team to create processes for managing customer issues and pre-sales opportunities for a \$182 million scanner software portfolio.

- Drove to completion prototypes and patches for current customers and "big deal" solutions for world-wide business opportunities ranging up to millions of dollars.
- Directed prioritization meetings to obtain cross-functional alignment.
- Managed off-shore developers and testers to achieve customer satisfaction and contract award goals.
- Debugged code written in C++ and MFC, verified fixes, and determined deployment strategy.

### Scanner and Camera Product Engineer and Program Manager (1997-2013)

Managed the requirements, schedule and software solution life-cycle for HP's market leading scanners and HP Photosmart cameras.

## Certified Scrum Master (2009-2012)

Led the team transition from a waterfall product life-cycle to using Agile. Managed the Scrum process to ensure the Scrum values, practices and rules were enacted and enforced.

# Software Developer (1993-2003)

Developed code and maintained components shipped with HP Scanjet Scanner solutions, HP Photosmart Digital Cameras, HP Personal and Photo Printers and HP All-in-One devices.